ASHIK SHEZAN

I am Shezan currently working as a Data Engineer at Leadbook. Having a good grasp of modern scripting languages such as Python and JavaScript I have efficiency in web crawling, automation, data analysis, visualization, & so on. I have experience in the field of web development as well. I build web applications using Django & ReactJS. As a motivated self-learner and a programming enthusiast, I am always ready to face new challenges to take my skills to the next level.

□ ashikshezan@gmail.com

+8801776754123

Dhaka, Bangladesh

github.com/ashikshezan

EDUCATION

BSc in Computer Science & Engineering American International University-Bangladesh

2015 - Present

Higher Secondary Certificate Meherpur Govt. College

2011 - 2013

Secondary School Certificate

Meherpur Govt. School

2006 - 2011

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Engineer Leadbook

02/2021 - Present Singapore

Built to help marketers generate a constant supply of fresh leads. Responsibilities

- Data crawling, acquisition and analysis
- · Scripting and automating tasks

Freelance Developer Online Marketplaces

04/2020 - 01/2021

Achievements/Tasks

- · Completed a number of projects on automation & scripting with python
- Built RESTful web services with Django
- Worked with ReactJS to create SPA applications

Executive Member

Boiporun.com 01/2019 - 03/2019

Dhaka

Achievements

• It was a startup basically an online book shop where I assisted to build the database. Apart from that I also had the responsibility to communicate with the book publishers and writers. So while working here I had the opportunity to improve my communication skills.

SKILLS



SKILLS & APTITUDES

- A good understanding of Object-Oriented Programming
- Understanding of Data Structures & Algorithms
- Familiar to MVC/MVT designing pattern
- Knowledge of relational databases and REST-full API
- Workable knowledge of HTML and CSS and various CSS frameworks
- Working experience in data analysis python libraries such as pandas, matplotlib, plotly, scrapy, bs4, etc
- Understanding of Networking concepts like Request-response, JWT, Headers, HTTP verbs, TCP, DNS, etc.
- Very comfortable working in Linux env, version controlling & terminal
- Experience with SQL and NoSQL(MongoDB) database
- Familiar with Agile project management

INTERESTS

Learning new skills Watching Football

Keeping up with new technologies

Fascinated by Astronomy